It all started in a small village.
故事始於一座小村莊
One day, a rumble in the ground caused a rift under the cemetery,
有一天地底墓穴的底部 隨著地面微微震動而塌陷
from which a single man appeared.
一名男子自其中現身
He claimed to be the king of a once prosperous kingdom.
男子自稱是一千年前 滅亡的黃金之國的國王
He states that the once glorious land
昔日繁榮富強的黃金之國
continues to be held captive deep underground
在一名狂亂魔術師的肆虐之下
by the hands of a mad magician.
如今仍被囚於地下深處
To whomever defeats this magician,
“我將賜予擊敗魔術師之人
he offers everything his kingdom has.
我國擁有的一切”
After he imparts these words, he turns to dust and vanishes.
男子留下這句話後便化為塵埃消逝
DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
Keep it up, everyone.
各位，加把勁啊
We've only got a bit left after this dragon.
我們打倒這條龍後就只差一步
Let's go!
我們上！
We're completely prepared.
我們萬事俱備
Nothing can get in our way.
沒有導致敗北的因素
That's not true.
不對
We're hungry.
我們肚子餓了
Everyone's movements lack their usual edge.
大家的動作也不復以往的靈敏
We lost a day roaming around due to a misprint on our map.
由於地圖畫錯 我們浪費了整整一天到處徘徊
We walked into a trap and lost three days' worth of food.
中途被陷阱困住 失去了三天份的糧食
It's bothersome, but we should turn back for a bit after defeating the dragon.
雖然麻煩，但打倒龍之後先收隊好了
Laios!
萊歐斯哥哥！
What happened, Falin?
怎麼了？法琳
Did they cast a confusion spell on you?
你不會是中了混亂魔法吧？
Wh…
什…
What?
什麼？
You're kidding me.
不會吧
We're all dead? We're so deep in the dungeon.
我們會在迷宮最深處全軍覆沒？
R-Run.
你快逃
Laios.
萊歐斯
You're awake.
你醒啦
It looks like a magic spell got us out of the dungeon,
看來是魔法助我們逃出迷宮
but Falin's the only one we can't find.
但只少了法琳一人 我們到處都找不到她
She was eaten.
她被吞掉了
What?
什麼？
Her magic didn't work from inside the dragon's stomach.
她被吞進了龍腹之中 魔法對她不起作用
That can't be.
怎麼會？
She's probably still in the dungeon.
她多半還在迷宮裡
Let's go now to save her.
我立刻去救她
Hold on.
你先等一下
Honestly, it looks like almost everything we had was left behind in the dungeon.
老實說我們的行囊 幾乎都留在了迷宮裡
So we're basically cleaned out.
可以說我們現在幾乎是身無長物
What?
你說什麼？
And what's worse…
還有更令人頭疼的…
Chilchuck?
奇爾查克？
We just lost two of our party members.
我們剛失去了兩位隊友
RESIGNATION LETTER
（辭呈）
What's that?
那是什麼東西？
Apparently another party's been courting them for a while now.
他們好像很早之前 就收到其他隊伍的入隊邀請
What?
真的假的？
Exploring dungeons costs money
探索迷宮需要錢
for hiring companions, buying equipment, and getting food too.
僱用隊友、裝備開銷，還有伙食費
We can sell our current equipment and secure what funds we have now
我們可以賣掉現有的兵器 保障目前的經費
to switch to cheaper equipment.
並用那筆錢改買廉價裝備
As well as to pay for food, medicine, necessities, and new companions.
再一次購齊糧食 藥品、日用品，僱用新隊友
-Do we have enough? -Not in the slightest.
-我們錢夠嗎？ -完全不夠
My little sister will get digested while we get everything ready.
在我們籌措裝備的期間 我妹早就被消化了
There's that person who once revived someone from shreds, right?
好像曾有人被切成碎塊 還復活了，我沒記錯吧？
Have they ever revived someone from poop?
有冒險者從糞便狀態 重新活過來的案例嗎？
Never heard of that.
聽都沒聽過
I know we're short on cash,
雖然遇上了財務難題
but how about some food first?
但我們先吃點東西怎麼樣？
After all, our empty stomachs may have been why we failed.
畢竟飢餓是我們失利的原因所在
What should we eat?
要吃什麼好呢？
For cheap food, we could go to the bistro on the main street,
想吃便宜美食 可以去大道上的大眾餐廳
or there's The Laughing Wolf for bigger meals.
或是去分量較多的笑狼亭
Oh, but that pub's hard to pass up too!
哦，可是那間酒館也難以割捨！
Their soup dumplings are to die for.
那家餐廳的湯肉包超好吃
-No. -What?
-不 -什麼？
We need to get back to the dungeon.
我們得立刻回到迷宮
But as we are now…
可是繼續餓著肚子…
I have an idea.
我有一個想法
-You two will leave the party. -What?
-我要你們倆退出隊伍 -什麼？
Then, we'll sell your equipment and I'll enter the dungeon alone.
再來我會賣掉你們身上的裝備 獨自潛入迷宮
That's insane.
那麼做太魯莽了
Do you have a death wish?
你想送死嗎？
This way, we won't have to compromise on using quality equipment,
不，採用這個方案 就不必自降兵器性能
and I can get to the lowest floor while avoiding monsters if I'm alone.
我獨自行動可以避開魔物 盡量避免交戰，抵達最深層
It's not impossible.
並非不可能做到
It's all my fault in the first place.
會這樣本來就是我的錯
I can't put you two in danger too.
我不能拖著你們倆一起冒險
I'm going too, no matter what.
我絕對要一起去
I'll do anything to save Falin.
只要能救出法琳，我什麼都願意做
Falin is dear to me too.
因為我也很喜歡法琳
I won't drag you down.
我不會拖累你的
You know how strong my magic is.
你也清楚我的魔法有多麼強大吧？
Don't forget about my job, too.
要是你忘了我的職責就傷腦筋囉
You'll need me to open doors and disable traps.
休想說你不需要 解開門鎖或陷阱的人才
You guys…
你們兩個…
You really mean to go with me, right?
是真的有跟隨我的決心，是吧？
For better or for worse?
不管未來發生何事也一樣？
Y-Yeah.
是啊
We'll secure food from within the dungeon.
糧食要從迷宮內取得
-What?!
-什麼？
There are more than enough monsters in the dungeon.
迷宮內遍布魔物
That means an entire ecosystem exists inside.
換句話說迷宮裡 存在著完整的生態系統
Carnivorous monsters will have herbivorous monsters to feed on,
若有肉食性魔物 就會有草食性魔物供其捕食
and the herbivorous monsters eat plants
草食性魔物攝取的植物
that find nutrients from water, sunlight, and dirt.
自水、光及泥土中獲取養分
In other words, humans can eat in the dungeon too.
換句話說 人類也能在迷宮裡填飽肚子
So, what you're saying
你那番話的意思是
is that we'll eat monsters?
我們要吃魔物？
We'll eat monsters too.
應該說我們也會吃魔物
Think about our adventures until now.
想想我們迄今的冒險
I'm sure there were a lot of tasty-looking things.
相信應該出現過一些 看起來挺好吃的魔物
No, there's no way I'm eating those.
不要，我絕對吃不了
There are quite a bit of people who hunt monsters for food.
捕獵魔物果腹的人不在少數
You mean the criminals who can't come back on land?
你講的是不能回到地表的罪犯吧？
Even they get hospitalized all the time from food poisoning.
他們經常因為食物中毒被送醫耶
You said you'd do anything to save Falin.
你不是說願意做任何事救出法琳嗎？
I never said I'd eat monsters.
但我沒說要吃魔物
There's no time nor money. What other choice do we have?
我們沒錢，也沒時間 你還有其他辦法嗎？
But there's no point if we eat something weird
那我們也不能吃些奇怪的東西吧
and get stopped by food poisoning.
要是因食物中毒而無法行動 此行就沒意義了
Run away!
快逃啊！
Save us!
救救我們！
Looks like dungeon newbies.
剛才跑過去的那群人應該是迷宮新手
They're not cut out for this if they can't handle a monster like this.
連這種魔物都能讓他們徹底瓦解 那他們不太適合這一行
Hey, Laios?
怎麼了？萊歐斯
Let's make lunch out of this.
把這個當作今天的午餐吧
I refuse!
我拒絕！
No, absolutely not!
不要，我死都不要！
Isn't going straight to mushrooms a bit risky?
第一次就試蘑菇，會不會太危險了？
The dungeon food guide says it's food suited for beginners.
根據《迷宮美食指南》 這種蘑菇好像是挺適合新手的食材
It's meaty and has a mild taste.
肉質肥厚且味道溫和
-What is this book? -It looks pretty worn down.
-這什麼怪書？ -看上去有些年頭了
Let's go find more space to start a fire.
往前走一小段路 到開闊的地方生火吧
Wish we had one or two more ingredients, though.
要是能再多一、兩種食材就好了
Those steps are from a Huge Scorpion!
聽這腳步聲應該是大蠍子！
Could it be that he…
那傢伙該不會是想…
Despite being a dungeon, many people come and go,
雖說在迷宮內部 但人潮往來絡繹不絕
making it a bustling place for adventurers and merchants.
到處滿是冒險者和商人，熱鬧非凡
A former cemetery,
此地昔日曾為墓地
it was once a sacred place where villagers slept in peace.
是供村民安息的聖地
But once it was connected to the dungeon six years ago,
但自六年前與迷宮打通後
it became the liveliest place in the village.
便成了村裡最熱鬧的地方
They say monsters emerge from the depths of the dungeon.
相傳魔物來自迷宮深處
It is unclear whether a forbidden spell transformed terrestrial creatures
目前尚未釐清魔物 是否是因禁咒而外形驟變的地表生物
or if they were summoned from the world of monsters.
或者是自魔界召喚而來的生物
But they all have an odd appearance
不過魔物皆擁有奇特的外觀
and attack humans as if they have something to protect.
還會像是為了保護什麼似地攻擊人類
But that served as the only proof we have
然而上述幾點 正是證明受詛咒的黃金之都
that the cursed, formerly prosperous capital truly exists.
曾存在過的唯一證據
Don't kill it like a crayfish.
不要用抓螯蝦的手法抓牠啦
This is how you catch it, so it's easier than a crayfish.
這就是抓魔物大蠍子的方式 比螯蝦好抓多了
Hey.
我問你
You've been looking for a chance to eat monsters for a while, haven't you?
你從以前就一直在找機會吃魔物吧？
But that doesn't change the fact that I want to save my sister.
但我是真心想救出妹妹
Yeah, okay.
是喔，好啦
I've never told you this, but I love monsters.
我從來不曾透露，但其實我喜歡魔物
from their appearance and cries to their ecology.
我想瞭解牠們的模樣、叫聲、生態
I soon wanted to know their taste.
後來我變得也想嘗嘗牠們的獨特風味
He's a psychopath.
他是心理變態
Shouldn't we do this where there are fewer people?
找個人少的地方煮比較好吧？
It's hard to go back and forth for water.
為了取水來回跑很累人耶
So, how do we eat these?
所以這東西是要怎麼吃？
Let's try an orthodox approach.
用正統的方式，煮煮看吧
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
It's easy to cut from above, but there's resistance from the side.
直著下刀是挺好切的 但橫著下刀有阻力
When we fight against mushroom-type monsters,
對上蘑菇類的魔物時
slashing diagonally or horizontally might be less effective.
斜砍或橫砍可能沒什麼效果
That's good to know.
學到了一課
It looks like food if you slice it up.
切成薄片看起來就像食物了
I don't see it.
哪裡像？
Hey, hold on!
喂，等等！
We're eating it as is? What about the venom?
直接這麼吃？這樣毒液不會擴散嗎？
This scorpion's venom is safe to eat.
吃下這隻蠍子的毒對身體無礙
Really?
真的嗎？
That's what the book said, so I want to try it.
書上是這麼寫的，我想吃吃看
Blech.
嘔
Told you.
早就跟你說了
Hold it right there.
等一下
Scorpion Hot Pot, eh?
你們在煮蠍子鍋是吧？
But that method leaves much to be desired.
但那種煮法可不怎麼讓人佩服啊
Who are you?
你是誰？
When you eat this monster,
吃這種蠍子的時候
you must cut off the pincers, head, and legs.
一定得去掉螯、頭、腳和尾巴
The tail will upset your stomach.
尾巴會害人腹瀉
The book said it'd be fine.
可是書上寫吃了沒事啊
Or rather it just tastes bad.
確切來說，尾巴就是難吃
Also, cut up the body as well.
另外也在身體上切幾刀
It'll cook through more easily, and the juices create a delicious broth.
較容易煮熟，熬出高湯後 更能提升整鍋的美味度
It's easier to eat too.
這樣也好入口
And take out the internal organs.
內臟也要去除
They're bitter and have an awful texture.
因為內臟帶有苦味，還不好咬
As for the Walking Mushroom,
至於走路菇呢
throw out the bottom and three centimeters from the surface.
必須去掉尾端以及三公分厚度的表皮
The feet are tasty, so keep those.
腳的部分還挺好吃的，所以全放進去
The feet are tasty?
腳不錯吃嗎？
Yeah, they have a nice, unique smell, right?
沒錯，是不是有一股特別的香氣？
The smell of the feet, huh?
腳的味道？
This pot is too small.
這個鍋子小了點
Let's use mine.
用老夫的鍋子吧
You sure are prepared.
你準備得好充足喔
It feels like it's missing something.
只有蠍子和蘑菇 味道上稍嫌單調了些
Here.
用這個吧
Wait, there's no way I'll eat that.
等一下，那些不能拿來吃啦
-Marcille? -Not in a million years.
-瑪露希爾？ -絕對不能放
This is a cemetery, you know.
聽著，這裡可是墓地
Even if I'm okay with monsters,
就算我再怎麼不介意吃魔物
plants with roots are out of the question.
帶根的植物就是不行
Doesn't it look good enough with just this?
放這些魔物不就夠好吃了嗎？
-Marcille! -And who the hell are you?
-瑪露希爾！ -再說你是誰啊？
-Look up! -What?
-快抬頭！ -什麼？
A Slime!
史萊姆！
Dammit, it's covering my face.
糟糕，竟然蓋住了整張臉
Oh no, I can't cast any spells.
不妙，我沒辦法詠唱咒語
Thinking back, my first death was to a Slime.
想起來了，我第一次翹辮子 也是因為史萊姆
-Are you okay? -Yeah.
-你沒事吧？ -我沒事
It got in my nose, though.
不過是鼻孔裡進了一些史萊姆
Blow it out.
擤出來吧
You got rid of a Slime with just a knife?
你竟用刀擊退史萊姆？
It's simple if you know its composition.
只要瞭解牠的結構 輕輕鬆鬆就能做到
They may look amorphous,
史萊姆的結構看似不固定
but their composition is actually more structured than humans.
實際上卻比人類更具結構性
This is the inside of a Slime.
史萊姆的內臟呈現這種構造
Compared to humans, the stomach is flipped
與人類相比，牠的胃上下顛倒
and covers its internal organs and head with digestive fluids.
並且用消化液包覆其內臟及頭部
It senses the breathing of its prey and springs into action.
牠能感知獵物的呼吸 接著迅速撲向攻擊目標
So you're an easier target if you shout in a loud voice.
所以大喊大叫更容易遭到史萊姆攻擊
It's not edible like this,
這東西不做處理難以下嚥
but you can add citrus juice, and wash it thoroughly in hot water.
但可以用摻有 柑橘類果汁的熱水徹底洗淨
Then, wipe off the moisture
接著擦乾水氣
or rub it in salt and dry it in the sun.
或者是抹上鹽巴，放在日光下曬成乾
This makes a delicious delicacy.
高級食材就此完成
If possible, it's best to let it fast for two weeks.
最好讓史萊姆斷食兩週左右
Drying it takes time too.
曬乾也需要時間
This is a portable Slime drying net that I made myself.
這是老夫親手製作的 便攜式史萊姆曬網
Sandwich it like this
像這樣夾好史萊姆
and it dries as you walk around.
就能趁行走期間將牠曬成乾
It takes time until it's ready,
製成成品耗時不短
but here's the final product.
不過老夫身上有成品
Let's add this for today.
今天就加進這個吧
-But isn't it a delicacy? -It's fine.
-但這不是高級食材嗎？ -無妨
I've researched monster food in this dungeon for over ten years.
老夫在這座迷宮裡 研究了魔物料理超過十年
Nothing makes me happier than to hear someone is interested in Monster cuisine.
看見有人對魔物料理感興趣 老夫高興得不得了
Ten years?
十年？
Was the dungeon here that long?
迷宮那麼早就出現了？
Well, sit tight.
好，稍等片刻
It's ready.
完成了
HUGE SCORPION AND WALKING MUSHROOM HOT POT
（大蠍子佐走路菇火鍋）
Boiled Huge Scorpions turn red, huh?
原來煮熟的大蠍子會變紅啊？
It feels so different seeing it in person.
在書上看的跟親眼所見的 根本是天差地別
It smells kind of delicious.
感覺有一股很香的味道
The meat contracts when cooked,
蠍肉煮熟後會稍微縮水
so it comes apart easily.
所以能輕易剝離
You're right.
真的耶
This is delicious!
好吃！
Isn't it?
好吃吧？
It tastes so different based on how you cook it.
沒想到不同的烹飪方式 竟能讓味道天翻地覆
Right?
沒錯吧？
It's so good! I'm shocked!
好吃極了！我超震驚的！
Right?!
好吃吧？
Give me some too.
給我也來一碗
What is this?
這是什麼？
Dried Slime innards.
曬乾的史萊姆內臟
It's good!
超好吃！
So, this is how you eat Slimes?
原來史萊姆得這樣吃啊？
It also tastes good soaked in fruit juice.
泡在果汁裡吃也不賴
And these tree roots are so nice and fluffy.
這些樹根好綿軟，味道絕佳
They're not technically roots.
確切來說，那不是樹根
They're tree trunks that grow upside down in the dungeon.
而是迷宮裡反向生長的植物枝幹
This algae is so soft and tasty.
藻類也是入口即化，真好吃
Does this grow in the dungeon too?
這也是迷宮裡生長的植物？
That's just normal algae that grows in humid places.
那是普通藻類 通常會在潮濕地帶冒出來
I can't believe all this is from the dungeon we've been walking through.
想不到我們平日裡 經常來的迷宮有這些食材
I'm stuffed.
我吃得好飽
We still haven't heard your name.
話說你沒報上名字呢
My name is Senshi.
老夫叫先西
It means "researcher" in Dwarvish.
在矮人語中意指“探索者”
I'm Laios.
我是萊歐斯
That's Marcille the magic-user and Chilchuck the picklock.
他們是魔法師瑪露希爾 以及開鎖師奇爾查克
Looks like you're on a mission.
你們這趟旅程似乎有隱情
Yes, that's right.
對，可以這麼說
One of our companions got eaten by a monster in the lower levels.
我們有個隊友在迷宮下層 被魔物吞進肚
We want to save her before she gets digested.
想趕在她被消化前救人
By a monster? What kind?
被魔物吞了？是什麼魔物？
A dragon with deep-red scales.
是一條龍，通體紅鱗的龍
Deep-red scales?
通體紅鱗、迷宮下層
The Red Dragon?
是炎龍嗎？
To maintain their large bodies,
龍為保持其碩大無比的身軀
dragons spend most of their days sleeping.
幾乎時刻處在沉睡當中
They also digest much more slowly than other monsters.
消化速度應該也比其他魔物慢得多
I hope so.
但願如此
Please.
拜託你
Would you allow me to accompany you?
可以讓老夫同行嗎？
You're more than welcome to.
我們當然是樂意之至
It'd be a huge help to us as well.
有你的加入，對我們也是一大助力
Really?
真的嗎？
-Thank you. -Likewise.
-那真是太感激了 -彼此彼此
I've dreamt of cooking the Red Dragon for many years.
料理炎龍是老夫長年以來的夢想
The Red Dragon.
炎龍啊
Maybe I should go for the traditional steak, or perhaps a burger.
依老夫看，應該拿來做 經典的龍排或龍肉堡吧
Shabu-shabu is great too.
涮涮鍋也是難以捨棄的選擇
No, if I have eggs, a Dragon and Egg bowl would be good.
不，手邊有蛋的話 還能做親子蓋飯呢
Is it okay to eat that?
“炎龍是可以吃的嗎？”
It was on everyone's mind, but no one said a word.
心中不免冒出如此疑問 卻沒有一人說出口
Second basement floor.
地下二層
Unlike the cemetery on the first basement floor,
這一層不同於 村中墓地所在的地下一層
an abnormal view spreads out before them.
出現在眼前的是不同尋常的景象
According to academics,
依學者的說法
this is the spire of the Golden Castle, which is located deep underground.
這一層大概落在 沉眠地底深處的黃金城堡尖塔處
I've always wondered about this,
我一直很好奇
but how do those trees not go above ground at this height?
依那些樹的高度 為什麼不會穿透地表？
Well, a curse made this dungeon.
這個嘛，或許是因為這座迷宮 是因詛咒而生吧
Marcille, are you okay?
瑪露希爾，你沒事吧？
I tripped on a gap in the bridge.
我不小心勾到橋的縫隙了
We've walked quite a way.
我們也走了不少路
You must be tired.
你應該累了
Let's find a campsite and stop early for today.
找個地方紮營，今天早點休息好了
We spent a night in a hollow tree here before, didn't we?
我們以前好像在 這附近的大樹空心處度過一夜吧？
Yeah, we did.
是啊，的確是耶
I burned myself trying to make pork soup.
當時我想煮豬肉湯，卻把自己燙傷了
Soup…
湯…
Are you hungry?
肚子餓了嗎？
I have some scorpion broth from lunch today.
老夫身上還有一點 中午吃剩的蠍子肉汁
I don't want it.
我不要
Well, then.
那麼，我想想
Let's go hunt a monster for dinner.
捉點煮晚餐時用得上的魔物好了
Jeez.
天啊
-What're you in the mood for? -What?
-瑪露希爾，你想吃什麼？ -什麼？
I'll do my best to match your request.
你有要求的話，我會盡力滿足你
You say that, but…
說是這麼說，但是…
We're eating monsters, right?
我們還是得吃魔物吧？
Ugh, I'm fine with anything as long as it's edible.
算了，只要能入口，吃什麼都好
What kind of monsters live around here?
這一帶有哪些魔物出沒？
Let's see…
我看看…
Big Bats and Giant Rats.
有大蝙蝠和大老鼠
I don't want anything unsanitary.
我堅決不接受不衛生的物種
Forest Goblins.
森林哥布林
Demi-humans are a no-go.
亞人種不考慮
Living Armor.
會動的鎧甲
Metal?
金屬類？
Isn't there anything more normal, like birds or tree fruits?
就沒有正常點的嗎？ 好比鳥類或果實這種的
There's always that one person
世上就是有這種人
who shoots down every idea after agreeing to eat anything.
嘴上說“吃什麼都好” 卻駁回我們的每一項提議
I don't think I'm asking for much.
我哪有那麼任性啦
There are normal monsters, but those don't attack humans,
普通的魔物有是有 但牠們不會主動攻擊人類
so they'll require more preparation.
想獵捕牠們需要做些準備
There's no such thing as a free lunch.
鴨子不會帶著蔥送上門來
Sorry, that's true.
抱歉，你說得很對
But you know,
但這裡可是迷宮
we might run into a monster holding a flesh-eating lunch.
我們說不定會遇上 身上帶著食人蔥的怪物鴨
Let's try to enjoy this!
我們就多多期待吧！
Not very optimistic about this.
我沒辦法跟你一樣樂觀
Well, there are lots of fruits during this season.
不過啊，這個季節的 樹果和果實多到數不清
Really?
真的嗎？
Yeah.
真的
See? I knew it'd be tree fruit from Man-eating Plants.
你們看，果然是食人植物的果實
Marcille, that's incorrect.
瑪露希爾，你說錯了
Man-eating Plants are just the common name.
“食人植物”是通用名稱
That flower, for example, is a Baraselia.
像是那朵花 其正式名稱為巴拉瑟莉雅
It mainly grows on monster trails
是主要生長於獸徑的野生植物
shooting out a mucus reminiscent of spider webs.
它會噴出類似蜘蛛絲的黏液
When a creature touches the mucus, it reflexively pulls them in.
生物一旦觸及，便會自動拉近
It wraps around things that move, but it doesn't digest them.
它會纏住移動的物體 但本身不具消化能力
It makes them into compost.
是一種自行製作堆肥的植物
But it sometimes uses humans for nutrients, right?
可是這些花有時也會以人類為食 獲取營養不是嗎？
The vegetables you usually eat
你平常食用的蔬菜
can be traced back to dead remains and animal dung.
追本溯源也是由 生物的排泄物或屍體澆灌而成
I can't fault that logic, but…
雖然我對你的想法沒什麼意見…
It's fine.
放心吧
It's still only the second basement floor.
這還只是地下二層
Someone would notice if a corpse rolled by here.
一旦有屍體滾在這附近 肯定會有人立刻發現
They have people to retrieve corpses,
畢竟有屍體回收業者在嘛 先不提深層
and no one would get eaten by a monster in a place like this.
沒有人會在淺層淪為魔物的口中食啦
You think so?
是這樣嗎？
I don't think we can pluck them in secret.
要偷偷摘下來似乎有難度
We'll have to fight.
我們只能戰鬥了
Move over.
你們別擋路
I'll get rid of them in one shot.
看我一招解決對方
Sperae Yeptum Rufermus.
斯帕拉葉耶普圖姆盧非姆斯
Alamandras Proju.
阿拉曼德拉斯普羅休
Nexant Aslam.
聶克桑德阿斯拉姆
Stop, you moron!
住手，蠢姑娘！
Why?
為什麼？
Do you want the fruit to get hit by your magic too?
你打算施法連花帶果一塊吹下來嗎？
Only take as much as you'll eat. This rule is absolute.
只取我們要吃的分量即可，這是鐵則
This isn't the time for that!
現在不是說這些的時候！
No, let go of me!
不要，放開我！
They can't digest people?
說什麼花不具消化功能？
But they're totally eating them!
這不是將整個人吃下去了嗎？
What? Some of them can digest things, though.
什麼？有些是有消化功能的啊
Depends on the plant type.
主要取決於物種
The one that has a hold of you
順帶一提，現在抓住你的
is a parasite type that plants seeds inside your skin.
是一種寄生型物種 會在皮膚底下播種
That's the worst kind!
我最討厭這種類型了！
Try to stay still, Marcille.
不要亂動，瑪露希爾
Plant-based monsters basically have several limbs.
植物型魔物通常擁有多條藤蔓
It'll take forever to fight them one at a time.
要是一一對付的話 砍到天黑也砍不完
For swords, there's only one sure-fire spot.
持劍的話只需瞄準一處攻擊
The root.
那就是根部
Ouch…
痛死我了…
Are you okay?
沒受傷吧？
Yeah, thanks Laios.
沒有，謝了，萊歐斯
-How was it? -What?
-感覺如何？ -什麼？
This is Shadowtail, a plant-based parasite that buries seeds
這叫影尾，是一種 在生物皮膚底下播種的
inside the skin of living creatures.
捕食類寄生植物
Unlike the Baraselia, which is strong enough to break bones,
其藤蔓不像巴拉瑟莉雅 強勁到足以讓獵物骨折
the Shadowtail needs to capture its prey without killing them.
影尾必須困住並活捉它的獵物
It uses a delicate balance,
因此絞緊的力道
immobilizing its prey without making it uncomfortable.
呈現絕妙的平衡 讓獵物無法掙脫卻不會感到不適
I feel like it'd feel really good. How did you feel?
我覺得應該特別舒適，你覺得呢？
I made her mad again.
我又惹她生氣了
Even I thought you were a bit much.
連我都覺得你剛才那番話有點超過
First, steam it lightly.
首先稍微蒸一下
Cut around the stem in a circle.
接著沿蒂頭切出一個圓
Twist it a bit and pull to get the seeds out.
略為施力，扭一扭後往外拔 就能將籽徹底去除
-Wow. -Peel the skin off,
-哇 -削掉外皮
beat the skin to make it soft,
然後使勁搗爛弄軟
and cover the pan with it.
鋪在平底鍋裡
Grind up the unripe fruit, adding Slime and some scorpion broth,
磨碎未成熟的果實 加入史萊姆和少量蠍子肉汁
mixing until it thickens.
攪拌至黏稠
Once it gets smooth, add the rest of the scorpion broth
變得順滑後再放入剩下的蠍子肉汁
and chunks of tree fruit.
以及切塊的樹果
Mix it a bit and pour it into the frying pan.
粗略攪拌後倒進平底鍋
Cook it a bit.
加熱片刻
I want to see if we can grow it on the surface.
我想試試能不能在地表上種植
Of course, we can't.
想也知道不可以
No!
不！
When it starts bubbling, add the rest of the fruit.
當表面開始冒泡，再撒剩下的果實
All right.
很好
It's done.
完成了
MAN-EATING PLANTS FRUIT TART
（食人植物餡餅）
A tart?
這是餡餅？
At least, it looks like it.
看起來像而已
The crust is just a non-stick coating. You can leave it.
餅皮是用來防止燒焦沾鍋的 留著不吃也行
It's salt-flavored. That's not what I expected.
是鹹的耶，跟我想像中的味道不一樣
Yeah, it's good.
是啊，挺好吃的
Try it, Marcille. You'll probably like it.
吃吃看嘛，瑪露希爾 你應該會喜歡這個味道
None of the plants that ate people are in it, right?
裡面真的沒放吞了屍體的植物吧？
No, if we used the gelatin from those plants,
沒有，如果用了那種植物儲存的明膠
it would've turned out even better.
定型時原本會更漂亮
The Slime didn't solidify well.
但是用史萊姆就不太能固定
This is delicious.
這個好好吃
The compost-type plants' fruit is fresh and sweet.
堆肥型植物的果實既水潤又甘甜
The digestion-type plants' is more compact and rich.
消化型植物的果肉緊實而風味濃郁
But I wonder if that's okay.
但是那樣好嗎？
Doesn't that mean they get eaten by other animals?
果實好吃的話 代表對其他動物來說是美食吧？
All this fruit they make gets taken away.
那植物辛苦結出的果實 不就會被吃光嗎？
That's how a carnivorous plant works.
那就和肉食性植物的生態有關
They use them to capture prey for nourishment.
它會捕捉目標動物以獲取養分
Oh, I see.
喔，也對
I wonder if this sweetness is one of their tricks then.
那這麼美味也是一種誘捕手段吧
Now I get it.
現在我懂了
I'm so happy you're getting interested.
你開始感興趣了，我好欣慰
Stop that!
別說了！
What'll we do with that corpse?
所以那具屍體要怎麼處理？
We don't have time to go back to town.
我們現在也無法回到城鎮
Want me to revive it with magic?
要我施魔法讓他復活嗎？
No, there's a chance it won't work.
不用了，也可能會失敗
Maybe someone will take it if we leave it in the open.
放到視野好的地方，應該有人會撿走
Yeah.
說得沒錯
Let's make it visible.
盡可能讓他顯眼一點
I've seen this at execution sites.
我在刑場見過這種景象
Marcille had a nightmare that night.
當晚瑪露希爾做了惡夢
Dungeon food.
迷宮飯
Eat or be eaten.
不是吃，就是被吃
There is no hierarchy.
迷宮裡沒有上下之分
Eating is a privilege for those who live.
唯有進食是生者的特權
Dungeon food.
迷宮飯
Oh, dungeon food.
哦，迷宮飯
DELICIOUS IN DUNGEON
《迷宮飯》
Subtitle translation by: Chul Kim
字幕翻譯：劉維容